

Pritam Honrao

Lohegaon Pune -Maharashtra Mobile-8806959009 Email ID: pritamhonrao100@gmail.com

Career Objective

Looking forward to making a strong career in a reputed IT industry where I can expand my knowledge of Exchange admin or System admin.

Professional Summary

Proactive and result -driven IT administrator with 10 years of experience in Azure cloud services, Onpremises Active directory, and Microsoft Exchange management. Expertise in deploying, configuring and securing cloud and on-premises environments to ensure optimal performance and compliance.

1) Professional Experience

Company: Tech Mahindra Ltd.

22 Dec 2016 to till date

Job Role: Associate System Engineer

- Manage and Maintain Microsoft Exchange as well as Microsoft Office 365.
- End to end troubleshooting for all inbound/outbound email delivery failures.
- Troubleshooting Web Mail and Active sync issues.
- Managing Outlook Webmail Access and ActiveSync of Email Accounts for Employees located worldwide.
- On boarding &off boarding of the mailbox from On-Premises Exchange to office 365 &vice versa.
- Checking, filtering, tracking and releasing quarantined emails using Cisco Iron Port Email Gateway and EOP Gateway.

- Mailbox Creation, Modification, Movement, Quota increase and delegate rights.
- Group Mail Creation/deletion/modification and delegation.
- Creation and modification of Shared, Resource mailbox.
- Monitoring/Managing Queues on Exchange 2013.
- Query base DL creation, modification. Moderation and delegation.
- Creating and Maintaining Security and Distribution Groups with the secured level of user access.
- Checking Daily report for Spammer domains & blacklisted domains.
- User ID Migration from one domain to another using ADMT tool.
- creation and mapping of security groups
- Troubleshooting for SPAM issues.
- MS Intune and MDM\MAM Enrolment
- Handling Escalated tickets/issues by Team.
- OU movement, User account enable\ disable

2) Professional Experience

Company: Comnet Solution Pvt Ltd

Client: WNS Global Services

16 Jun 2015 to 21 Dec 2016

Job Role: Technical support Engineer

- Installation of Windows 2000, Win XP, win 7, and Win 8 Operating Systems.
- Installing, Configuring, managing of Microsoft product
- MS Outlook: email account configuration (Microsoft Exchange server)
- Installing and configuring new hardware and software and third-Party Software.
- Antivirus installation and Management.
- Configuration of office 365 and troubleshooting.
- Working on BMC remedy ticketing tool
- Each and every ticket solving within SLA
- Remotely solve problems using Team Viewer, Windows remote assistance.

- Providing Remote Support to Onsite user through WebEx session.
- Installation and Configuring VPN connections.
- Support to Polycom Device National and International VC Call.
- Troubleshooting Hardware / Software related issues for both Laptop / Desktop.
- Adding/moving users to their respective VLAN Id.
- PC assembling, partitioning and installation.
- Installation of printer.
- Antivirus known and installation: Quick Heal, AVG and Kaspersky, Symantec
- Product of Microsoft office 2000,03,07,2010,2013 and LYNC 2010.
- Creating, configuring, managing, securing and troubleshooting File, Print resources
- Take machine in LAN. And add in Domain Network of the computer.
- Co-ordination with vendor for replacement, repair and standby material and delivery of Any IT equipment, Quotation, Preparing compressive sheet and forward for approval. Preparing and Maintaining Vendor's escalation matrix.

3) Professional Experience

Company: Crest-Premedia solution Pvt, ltd.

Feb 2013 to 31 Dec 2014.

Job Role: Desktop support Engineer

- Installation of Windows 7 and Win 8 Operating Systems.
- Installing, Configuring, managing of Microsoft product
- MS Outlook: email account configuration (Microsoft Exchange server)
- Installing and configuring new hardware and software and third-Party Software.
- Antivirus installation and Management.
- Configuration of office 365 and troubleshooting.
- Working on BMC remedy ticketing tool
- Each and every ticket solving within SLA
- Remotely solve problems using Team Viewer, Windows remote assistance.

- Providing Remote Support to Onsite user through WebEx session.
- Installation and Configuring VPN connections.
- Support to Polycom Device National and International VC Call.
- Installation, Configuration & troubleshooting software like Microsoft Office (office 2007, 2010 and 2013), Lync (office communicator) and other basic software
- Worked on Network printer installation, configuration and troubleshooting
- Operating system, software, network and hardware related troubleshooting
- Coordination with internal team and external team for IT support.

4) Professional Experience

• Company: I source info system Pvt. Ltd.

Jan-2012 to Feb 2013

- **Job Role:** Desktop Support Engineer
- Provided support for a highly randomized environment of 275computers.
- Monitoring and resolving issues in our domain
- Installation of windows 7 and XP.
- Software Installation
- Outlook installation of Ms office 2007,2010,2013 & troubleshooting
- Installation of network printer and USB printer
- Configuring office 365 and troubleshooting
- Working on Ticketing tool like Manage Engine
- Each and every problem solve within SLA
- Lotus note Configuration.
- Installation of all third-party software.
- Backup & Restore
- Password Reset by admin tools
- Laptop Configuration and connectivity of Wi-Fi devices

- SCCM Client installation & troubleshooting
- IP phone Configuration.
- Patches installation.
- Solving Issus through Remote desktop connection and Team viewer
- Vendor management and coordinate with Dell, HP and Lenovo
- CCTV monitoring
- Installation of Lync
- Inventory management
- Installation of antivirus & updating
- Troubleshooting desktop related issues.
- Troubleshooting operating systems configuration related issues.
- Troubleshooting Microsoft Office Outlook and others.
- Troubleshooting antivirus related issues and updates.
- Configuration of systems over wireless networks and troubleshooting.
- Working and fixing network related problems.

Professional Qualification

- Completed Course MCITP From GNS Technologic
- Computer Hardware and Networking
- Microsoft Certified System Engineer

Academic Qualification

- S.S.C And H.S.C (Science) From Pune Board
- Diploma in Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering from M.S.B.T.E Mumbai

Personal Information

• Name: Pritam Honrao

• Sex : Male

• Marital Status : Married

• Language Know: English, Hindi, Marathi

Date: Place: Pune

Pritam Honrao